simplecast.com 2019-10-21

# Privacy Policy - Simplecast

## Simplecast is committed to transparency and protecting your privacy. 

Welcome to Simplecast. Simplecast cares about online privacy and takes the security of your information very seriously. This policy covers the collection and usage of your personal information. Please read it carefully. If you have any questions concerning our privacy policy, send us a message at [help@simplecast.com](mailto:help@simplecast.com) .

This Privacy Policy covers the collection and usage of your personal information whenever you visit on Simplecast.com, or any other website created with Simplecast (collectively, the “Simplecast Websites”). Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “you,” “your,” and “user” shall refer to any user and/or visitor of any of the Simplecast Websites. Unless explicitly stated otherwise, your use of any of the Simplecast Websites, and/or any of the Products and Services offered or provided by Simplecast, including the addition of new properties, shall be governed by this Privacy Policy and the Simplecast Terms and Conditions Agreement, where applicable, whether or not you register as a user. Be advised that we may also offer or provide services from time to time that are governed by the privacy policy of the respective service providers, and you agree to be further bound by any rules that are applicable to Simplecast with respect to the service providers. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, at our sole and absolute discretion.

## Information Collection and Use by Simplecast.

  * Simplecast collects user submitted information such as name and email address to send notifications to those users relating to, without limitation, the Simplecast service, special events, contests and special offers. As is standard practice on many corporate websites, Simplecast also logs non-personally identifiable information which includes, without limitation, IP address, profile information, aggregate user data, and browser type, from users of the Simplecast Websites. This data is used to improve the Simplecast Websites services, to analyze trends, to administer the the Simplecast Websites, to track user movement around the Simplecast Websites and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Simplecast will not use the information collected to market directly to that person. This non-personally-identifiable information may be shared with third-parties to provide more relevant services and advertisements to users. User IP addresses are recorded for security and monitoring purposes.
  * Simplecast may use pixel tags (tiny graphic images) to tell us what parts of the Simplecast Websites have been visited or to measure the effectiveness of searches users perform on the Simplecast Websites. Pixel tags also enable us to send email messages in a format users can read, and they also tell us whether emails have been opened to assure that we’re only sending email messages that are of interest to our users. Simplecast stores all of this information in a secure database.

**Use of Cookies.** Like most companies, Simplecast uses cookies to store user preferences and to record session information for various purposes, including, without limitation, market research to help us determine how best to provide useful information to users and to understand which parts of the Simplecast Websites and internet services are of most interest to them, to customize the newsletter, advertising, and Web page content based on browser type and user profile information, to help track usage to help us understand which parts of the Simplecast Websites are the most popular, where our users are going, and how much time they spend there, to make usage of the Simplecast Websites even more rewarding as well as to study the effectiveness of our communications with users and to customize each user’s experience and provide greater convenience. Please rest assured, Simplecast doesn’t link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on the Simplecast Websites. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies or notify you when a cookie is set. Each browser is different, so check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences; however, you must enable cookies from Simplecast in order to use most functions on the site.

[View Simplecast’s Cookie Declaration and adjust your tracking preferences](https://simplecast.com/cookie-declaration/)

## Sharing / Disclosure.

  * From time to time, Simplecast or a Simplecast Partner may sponsor a promotion, sweepstakes, or contest on the Simplecast Websites. In such cases users may be asked to provide personal information including name, email address or home address, or to answer questions in order to participate. Simplecast may transfer such personal information to certain ad partners that you have explicitly requested to receive information from. It will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the personal information and whose privacy statement will apply.
  * Simplecast does not sell or rent your contact information to marketers. To help us provide superior service, we may share your personal information with third parties who will safeguard it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. There are also times when it may be advantageous for Simplecast to make certain personal information about you available to companies that Simplecast has a strategic relationship with or that perform work for Simplecast to provide products and services to you on our behalf. These companies may help us process information, deliver products to you, manage and enhance customer data, provide customer service, assess your interest in our products and services, or conduct customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are also obligated to protect your personal information in accordance with Simplecast’s policies. Without such information being made available, it would be difficult for you to purchase products, have products delivered to you, receive customer service, provide us feedback to improve our products and services, or access certain services, offers, and content on the Simplecast website.
  * Simplecast will not disclose personal information to any third-party unless in accordance with Section 10 of this Privacy Policy.
  * Simplecast reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of Simplecast or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest.

**Links to Third-Party Websites.** Simplecast contains links to third party websites. Simplecast is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of or on other websites. When linking to another website, a user should read the privacy policy stated on that website. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on the Simplecast Websites.

**Notice Regarding the Privacy of Children Under 13.** None of the Simplecast Websites are directed to or recommended for use by children under the age of 13. We operate the Simplecast Websites in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, and do not permit registration by, and will not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from, anyone under 13 years of age.

**Tracking User Activity.** Simplecast may send email messages which use or otherwise contain a “click-through URL” that is linked to content on the Simplecast Websites. When the “click-through URL” is clicked on or otherwise activated, the party who clicked on or otherwise activated the “click-through URL” is taken through the Simplecast web server(s) before arriving at the destination page. During this process, “click-through data” is collected by Simplecast, which may include, without limitation, data that helps us determine interest in particular topics and data that helps us measure the effectiveness of the communications we send out. If you prefer not to be tracked in this manner, simply avoid clicking on or otherwise activating text or graphic links in the email. We do not authorize third party services to track our customers’ RSS feeds or shows without both Simplecast and our customers’ permission.

**Concerning Content you Add to Simplecast.** Any content that you add, upload, post, publish, or otherwise disseminate through the Products and Services offered by Simplecast should be considered fully accessible by the public and not private. Such content, once published, may immediately become accessible on search engines and other sites. It is important that you are mindful of this fact.

**Email Preferences / Opting-Out.** Occasionally, Simplecast may send email regarding news, promotions, surveys, updates, or offers related to Simplecast. Users who no longer wish to receive these emails may choose not to by simply opting-out. To opt-out, simply click on the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email. It is important to note, users cannot opt-out of email regarding legal notices or user account changes.

**Compliance with Law.** Simplecast may preserve any Content contained on or about its web server(s) and may also disclose such Content if required to do so by law or in the good faith that preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (a) comply with a search warrant or other legal process received by Simplecast; (b) enforce the Terms and Conditions; (c) respond to claims that any Content violates the rights of third-parties; or (d) protect the rights, property or personal safety of Simplecast, its users and the public.

**Data Transmission.** You acknowledge and agree that the technical processing and transmission of the Products and Services, including any of your Content, may involve (a) transmissions over various networks; and (b) changes to conform and adapt to the technical requirements of connecting the networks or devices.

**Security.** Simplecast Accounts are secured by user-created (as applicable) passwords. Simplecast takes precautions to ensure that account information is kept private through reasonable measures such as encryption to protect private information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to such private information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note, however, that Simplecast cannot and does not guarantee the security of user account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user account information at any time. Users are urged to take precautions to protect their personal data by changing passwords often, using a combination of letters and numbers, and using a secure web browser. For any additional information about the security measures Simplecast uses on the Simplecast Websites, please contact us at [privacy@simplecast.com](mailto:privacy@simplecast.com).

**Amendments and Changes to this Privacy Policy.** From time to time, Simplecast may make changes to this Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will post them on this URL to make users aware of what the changes are so users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. A user is bound by any minor changes to the Privacy Policy when she or he uses the the Simplecast Websites after those changes have been posted. If, however, we are going to use a user’s personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify by posting a notice on Simplecast for 30 days.

**Accessibility Statement** Simplecast is committed to providing access to all users. We use the WCAG 2.1 AA level as our goal for access, and have partnered with accessibility consultant, Oleb Media, to provide us UX testing for a representative range of people with sensory, cognitive, and mobility related impairments. All of our players meet WCAG 2.1 A and AA levels, and we are working hard to update our website and user dashboard. If you run into any access problems on our site, please contact [legal@simplecast.com](mailto:legal@simplecast.com).

See our [Data Processing Addendum](https://simplecast.com/dpa/)

_Last updated May 25, 2018_

### All plans come with a 14-day free trial and you can cancel anytime.
